#### Contact

glen@buonvia.com

www.linkedin.com/in/glencarl (LinkedIn) www.zerocog.us (Company)

## Top Skills

Rumble Cloud

**Python** 

**Project Management** 

## Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

## Certifications

**PMP** 

#### Honors-Awards

NASA Software of the Year Award for Center TRACON Automation System

**CSC Web Services Award** 

AIAA Outstanding Career Enhancement National Award

AIAA Outstanding Public Policy National Award

AIAA Special Service Citation for outstanding work creating / maintaining Career Enhancement web site

#### **Patents**

METHOD AND APPARATUS FOR VIDEO-ENHANCED NETWORKED SALES PROCESS COMMUNICATIONS

# Glen CARL

Software Systems Engineer / Researcher, and PMP® Capitola, California, United States

# Summary

Project Management Professional (PMP)® / Software Engineer / Systems Integrator. Aerospace Operations domain expertise. Enjoys Lean Startup methodology.

Currently, developing statistical visualization software to analyze model comparisons of time series data with confidence interval thresholds. The trending icons (emojis) of scorecard has been very useful for researchers to demonstrate the capabilities of enhancements to models.

Other research includes, cloud services, machine learning, OpenApi, user web services, and automation of services. Research demands learning new technologies for full stack systems. Challenges include working with extremely large data sets that are related of meteorological and oceanographic data.

Specialties: Program/Project management, scientific applications programming, system integration, architecture, development, configuration management, start up businesses, intellectual property.

Constantly analyzing several business ideas.

# Experience

Ocog Inc.

Co-Founder, Researcher, Engineer April 2009 - Present (15 years 11 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Co-Founder of a new media company with an immediate focus on mobile device media with the kick of augmented reality. In addition, we have the patent pending "401(b) program". Part of the 401(b) program has resulted in several start-up company initiatives. Develop IP for many products.

Established 0cog as US Federal Contract service provider, CCR CAGE Code: 5YS23. Established contract services with Naval Research Laboratory (NRL) with focus on software statistics, project management, cloud computing, and software systems integration. Recent development has been a scorecard statistics analysis package to compare atmospheric modeling statistic data. In addition, developing verification systems to integrate with NCAR Model Evaluation Tools (MET), with the goal of providing standardized statistics of time series models.

Recent R&D has had a focus on Python 3 scientific web applications run in Docker and Singularity containers. Required to build Swagger OpenAPI Flask Restful interactive documentation. Included work with enhancing routing algorithms.

Current focus is on automated statistical verification software system tools, and machine learning (AI) of atmospheric models.

Other consulting services available at this time include program / project management and business analysis.

Via 0cog, was able to work on several start up products, and many start up companies. Learned flows of funding, legal needs for protecting intellectual property, contracts, facilities, development tools and project management many types of projects. Hosted groups focused on entrepreneurship, project management and the latest in mobile technology. The hosting included, consulting, facilitating discussions, and providing content of interest.

OS: Linux, WinOS, iOS

Languages: Python, FORTRAN, C/C++, Jquery, JavaScript, SQL

Shells: bash, csh, ksh

VM/Containers: VMWare, Docker, Singularity, AWS

Frameworks: Flask, Django, SharePoint, Drupal. Fabric, Celery, RabbitMQ,

Anaconda
Atlassian tools

### Identity Element

co-Founder, VP of Technology, Systems Software Engineering March 2012 - March 2016 (4 years 1 month)

Research and Development on patent pending technology. Founded as Showroom LLC, and now d.b.a. Identity Element. R&D has a focus on

authentication and verification of goods and services. Required research of issues regarding fraudulent goods, and how to verify `real` goods. Researched ways to use mobile technology to communicate the verification and worth of goods.

DeVine Consulting, Inc Program Manager (PMP) / Biz Dev / Software Engineer July 2007 - March 2010 (2 years 9 months) California

Project Management and Software Systems Integration, specializing in US Department of Defense systems. Consulting included mobile applications for private and government use. Researched and designed INTRANET communications for medical operations command. Managed the design to deployment of mobile devices to allow safety inspection of facilities. Major project was to transition a visualization system from research laboratory to operational command. Java, JBoss, C/C++, SQL, FORTRAN, SQL, JavaScript, jQuery, SharePoint, Python, Win-X, bash, csh, Linux, WinOS, VMWare

## DXC Technology

Project Management Professional (PMP) / Software Engineer December 2001 - July 2007 (5 years 8 months)

Monterey, California

Computer Sciences Corporation (CSC) (merger) Architect, develop and manage web services for Navy information distribution services. Project lead of many new programs. Supported and pioneered Information Assurance policies for web services architectures. Designed web interface for flight planning operations. Managed multiple contractors to build and security accredit a web services compliance system. Java, ADA, PHP, PERL, CGI, JavaScript, FORTRAN, SQL, Linux, JBoss, bash, csh, VMWare, Linux

## Lutris

Product Marketing Engineer / Staff Engineer January 2000 - August 2001 (1 year 8 months)

Santa Cruz. California

(dissolved). Provided competitive solutions for Internet companies, including support of a portal for mobile devices of the company Room33, in Stockholm, Sweden. Supported the marketing of the Lutris J2EE application server, with SQL databases, WinOS and Linux demonstrations at conferences, including

the mobile technology. Java, J2ME, Enhydra, Win-X, XML, C/C++, LDAP, SMTP, IMAP, SQL, bash, csh, Linux, WinOS, VMWare

Boeing Commercial Airplanes
Programmer Analyst
October 1996 - January 2000 (3 years 4 months)
Los Gatos, California

Jeppesen (subsidiary). Architect, develop and manage the development of software solutions for airline flight planning system. Design and developed a restricted area 4-D boundary area library. Designed and developed internal web search tools of flight planning documents. Designed and developed a web based time tracking tool to allow management to determine time spent by staff, and which customers demanded the most time. Designed the first portotype of web based interface use of command line entry for flight planners. C/C ++, FORTRAN, TCL, PERL, CGI, XML, bash, ksh, csh, SQL. Cygwin, HPUX, SunOS

Northrop Grumman Aerospace Systems 6 years 5 months

Programmer Analyst September 1994 - October 1996 (2 years 2 months) Mountain View, California

Sterling Software (acquired). Develop software solutions for NASA air traffic control research systems. Supported automated testing of new flight planning software which required use of `C/C++` tools to detect issues in forked processes. Enhanced the aircraft spacing algorithm with Golden Section optimization. C/C++, X, PERL, csh, SunOS, SGI, Cygwin

Programmer Analyst
June 1990 - September 1994 (4 years 4 months)
Mountain View, California

Applied Technology Associates (acquired). Develop software solutions for aerospace and defense systems. Focus of work was on military flight weapons simulator, and tracking systems for orbit / attitude estimation. Learned to operate the AV-8b Harrier. Supported requirements, design, development, unit test, integrate test and document software for very large software project. Supported software development role for many projects related to satellite tracking and orientation. C/C++, ADA, JOVIAL/JCL, FORTRAN, X, SQL, SunOS, SGI, AIX, SCO

United States Air Force Aircraft Armament Systems Specialist / Staff Sergeant July 1986 - July 1994 (8 years 1 month)

Ground crew for the aircraft armament systems for the A-7, F-4, and F-16 attack/fighter jets. Stationed with the Air National Guard units at Duluth, MN, Tucson, AZ and Fresno, CA. Inactive reserve from 1992-1994. Gained many skills as a mechanic, and learned how very fast moving pieces interact. Learned the skills to be safe on a flight line with operational jets and active armament. Learned skills to problem solve technical problems.

# Education

University of Arizona

Bachelor of Science, Aerospace · (1987 - 1990)

University of Minnesota-Duluth

Pre-Engineering · (1984 - 1986)

University of California, Santa Cruz C/Unix Programming Certificate, Computer Software Engineering · (1991 - 2005)

NASA Ames Research Center and US Navy (1994 - 2021)

Global Brain, Inc.

Project Management · (2002 - 2002)